const questionsArray = [
  {
    question:
      "1. Which among the following was the first Indian woman who went into space?",
    optionsArray: [
      "Kalpana Chawla",
      "Sunita Williams",
      "Koneru Humpy",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Kalpana Chawla",
  },
  {
    question: "2. Who was the first Indian to go to space?",
    optionsArray: [
      "Vikram Ambalal",
      "Ravish Malhotra",
      "Rakesh Sharma",
      "Nagapathi Bhat",
    ],
    answer: "Rakesh Sharma",
  },
  {
    question:
      "3. Who among the following was the first man to climb Mount Everest without supplemental oxygen?",
    optionsArray: [
      "Junko Tabei",
      "Reinhold Messner",
      "Duncan Chessell",
      "Phu Dorji",
    ],
    answer: "Reinhold Messner",
  },
  {
    question: "4. Who built the Jama Masjid?",
    optionsArray: ["Jahangir", "Akbar", "Imam Bukhari", "Shah Jahan"],
    answer: "Shah Jahan",
  },
  {
    question: "5. Who wrote the Indian National Anthem?",
    optionsArray: [
      "Bakim Chandra Chatterji",
      "Rabindranath Tagore",
      "Swami Vivekanand",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Rabindranath Tagore",
  },
  {
    question: "6. Who was the first Indian Scientist to win a Nobel Prize?",
    optionsArray: [
      "C.V Raman",
      "Amartya Sen",
      "Hargobind Khorana",
      "Subramanian Chrandrashekar",
    ],
    answer: "C.V Raman",
  },
  {
    question: "7. Who is the first Indian to win a Nobel Prize?",
    optionsArray: [
      "Rabindranath Tagore",
      "CV Raman",
      "Hargobind Khorana",
      "Mother Theresa",
    ],
    answer: "Rabindranath Tagore",
  },
  {
    question: "8. Who was the first Indian woman to win the Miss World Title?",
    optionsArray: [
      "Aishwarya Rai",
      "Sushmita Sen",
      "Reita Faria",
      "Diya Mirza",
    ],
    answer: "Reita Faria",
  },
  {
    question: "9. Who was the first President of India?",
    optionsArray: [
      "Abdul Kalam",
      "Lal Bahadur Shastri",
      "Dr. Rajendra Prasad",
      "Zakir Hussain",
    ],
    answer: "Dr. Rajendra Prasad",
  },
  {
    question: `10. Which of the following earned the name 'Flying Sikh'?`,
    optionsArray: [
      "Milkha Singh",
      "Lala Lajpat Rai",
      "Bhagat Singh",
      "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
    ],
    answer: "Milkha Singh",
  },
];

export default questionsArray;
